<resources>
    <string name="app_name">WelshMuseumApp</string>
    <string name="welsh_heritage">Welsh Heritage </string>
    <string name="crdffMuseum">Cardiff Museum</string>
    <string name="stFagans">St Fagans</string>
    <string name="rlm">Roman Legion Museum</string>
    <string name="exhibits_highlights">Exhibits Highlights</string>
    <string name="cardiffexhibitsSlider">
        The Cardiff National museum features a range of fascinating exhibits. A 220-million-year-old dinosaur footprint, discovered by four-year-old Lily in 2021 at Bendrick’s Bay, is now on display, belonging to an unknown herbivorous dinosaur from the Upper Triassic period.
        The oldest artifact is a 4.56-billion-year-old iron meteorite from Namibia, weighing 260kg, part of a collection of meteorites from around the world.
        Also on display is the Jenkins Vase, originally a Roman altar from Naples, transformed into a vase in the 18th century, depicting the marriage of Paris and Helen.
        Lastly, the foyer showcases Dracoraptor hanigani, the first ever theropod dinosaur skeleton found in Wales. Discovered in 2014, this ancient predator’s fossils and reconstructions offer a glimpse into its Jurassic past.
        (Images taken form Museum Wales)
    </string>
    <string name="cardiffexhibitsdesc">
        The National Museum Cardiff in Wales houses an extensive and eclectic collection, celebrating Welsh culture, natural history, art, and archaeology. The museums art galleries hold an impressive range of European paintings, including works by Van Gogh, Monet, and Welsh artists such as Gwen John. Archaeological displays feature prehistoric artifacts, Roman-era relics, and medieval treasures that trace Wales’s historical and cultural journey. With its hands-on exhibits, including an Evolution of Wales gallery and temporary exhibitions, the museum offers an immersive experience into both Welsh and international heritage.
    </string>

    <string name="stFagansSlider">
        St Fagans National Historical Museum offers a wealth of information about Welsh life, thanks to its collection of historic buildings and beautiful grounds. One of the key exhibits is the Hotel Vulcan, a former pub located on Adam Street in the Newtown area of Cardiff. Built in the 1830s, it was a central part of a thriving multicultural community known as "Little Ireland" due to its large Irish population. Initially, the Vulcan Hotel consisted of two townhouses, which were combined into a hotel, and later, after reconstruction in 1914-5, became the Vulcan Hotel.Another attraction is Nant Walter, a farm workers cottage built around 1770 in Carmarthenshire. The cottage was built of thick log walls made of clay, silt and straw, and the thatched roof was designed so that the house was cool in summer and warm in winter. The cottages small windows and thatched roof of mixed materials reflect the familys ingenuity.Finally, St. Fagans Castle, a Grade 1 Elizabethan manor, is a stunning museum attraction. Donated to the people of Wales in 1948, the castle is surrounded by carefully restored gardens, including an Italian garden, a thyme garden and a rose garden. The area with fish ponds, fountains and a mulberry grove offers visitors the opportunity to experience the beauty of the past while enjoying the splendor of the present.
    </string>
    <string name="stFagansdesc">
        The Historical Museum St. Fagans in Wales offers a fascinating journey through time. Set in a beautiful 100-acre park, the museum showcases more than 40 historic buildings, including a 16th-century farmhouse and a medieval church, bringing Wales past to life. Visitors can experience traditional Welsh life through interactive exhibits, crafts and live demonstrations. The museum also has extensive collections of Welsh art, costume and folk history. The highlight is St. Fagans Castle, a stunning Elizabethan mansion surrounded by beautiful gardens. It is an exciting and informative experience offering a unique perspective on the cultural heritage of Wales.
    </string>

    <string name="rlmSlider">
        The Roman Legion Museum in Caerleon offers an opportunity to get to know the military and civilian life of the Romans. Among the main exhibits are a 1st-century tablet, the oldest surviving script in Wales, and a memorial stone in honor of Thadia Wallaunius and her son Thadius Exuperatus. The museum also has one of the best stocks of Roman silver coins and the UKs largest collection of engraved gems discovered in the drain of the bathhouse. Visitors can relax in the Roman-style garden, which features plants used in Roman cooking and medicine. The museum also has a recreated barracks where you can get to know the daily life of Roman soldiers. The fortress towers of Caerleon feature part of the original bathhouse with spectacular sound and light effects, demonstrating an advanced Roman approach to bathing that continues to influence modern spa culture.  (Images taken form © Amgueddfa Cymru-National Museum Wales, © Hawlfraint y Goron / Crown Copyright) </string>
    <string name="rlmdesc">
        The video highlights the key exhibits of museum in Caerleon, starting with the only legionnaires barracks on public display in Europe. The remains of four long blocks of rooms with more spacious apartments for the centurion give an idea of the life of the Roman military.
        Next, the Caerleon Amphitheatre is shown, the most complete in Britain, where residents once enjoyed the brutal sights of combat.
        The museum also displays Roman household items such as bread coupons, a 3rd-century iron frying pan and rotten baby teeth.
        Finally, the event program of the National Museum of the Roman Legion brings Roman history to life through events such as soldier demonstrations, Roman cooking and saturnalia celebrations throughout the year.
    </string>


    <string name="immersive_experience">Immersive Experience</string>
    <string name="google_street_view">Google Street View</string>
    <string name="panomric_images">Panomric Images</string>
    <string name="google_street_viewTxt">Google Street View</string>
    <string name="exhibits_highlights_video">Exhibits Highlights Video</string>
    <string name="my_api_key">AIzaSyA1zGorXs18Cw0ysbAUxGxgpzzfhUujj_k</string>
    <string name="google_street_viewtxt">Google Street View</string>
    <string name="national_museum_cardiff">National Museum Cardiff</string>
    <string name="content_library">Content Library</string>
    <string name="events_and_news">Events and News</string>
    <string name="accessability_settings">Accessability Settings</string>
    <string name="change_english_to_welsh">Change English to Welsh</string>

    <string name="close">Close Menu</string>
    <string name="rlm_name">National Roman Legion Museum</string>
    <string name="stF_name">St Fagans Museum</string>
    <string name="menu">Menu</string>
    <string name="panoramic_image">Panoramic Image</string>
    <string name="_360_degree_tour">360 Degree Tour</string>
    <string name="talkback_feature">TalkBack Feature</string>
    <string name="returnBack">return</string>
    <string name="museum_name">Museum name</string>


    <string name="celebrated">Celebrated dates in Welsh calendar</string>
    <string name="welshBio">Dictionary of Welsh Biography</string>
    <string name="hwb">Hwb is national collection of Welsh digital educational resources</string>
    <string name="welshAcademy">The Welsh Academy English-Welsh Dictionary Online</string>
    <string name="y_ta">Y Termiadur Addysg</string>

    <string-array name="namesL">
        <item>@string/welshBio</item>
        <item>@string/welshAcademy</item>
        <item>@string/celebrated</item>
        <item>@string/y_ta</item>
        <item>@string/hwb</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="stDwynd">St Dwynwens Day</string>
    <string name="stDwyndDesc">Maybe its the views of soaring mountains that do it, but were a romantic bunch here! We even have our own patron saint of lovers. Forget Valentine\'s Day, 25 January is the most romantic day of the year in Wales. We give romantic gifts to loved ones to remember St Dwynwen a love struck lass who became a nun after being forbidden by her father from marrying the man she loved. Ahh.</string>
    <string name="DyddM">Dydd Miwsig Cymru</string>
    <string name="DyddMText">For Dydd Miwsig Cymru (Welsh Language Music Day) we celebrate Welsh language music of all forms, in all genres! The country is taken over with pop-up gigs and performances in all sorts of venues. Whether you’re into indie, rock, punk, funk, folk, electronica, hip hop or anything else, there’s incredible music being made in the Welsh language for you to discover.</string>
    <string name="GwylName">Gŵyl Fair y Canhwyllau</string>
    <string name="GwylDesc">
            Traditionally, Gŵyl Fair y Canhwyllau (Mary’s Festival of the Candles), celebrated on February 2, marked the coming of spring in Wales. Candles were lit and placed in windows and parlour games played. Though no longer a fixture on the calendar, candle-themed services take place in some churches to celebrate the date.
    </string>
    <string name="stDavid">St Davids Day</string>
    <string name="stDavidDesc">
        The national day of Wales - St Davids Day takes place on 1 March. Across the country there are street parades that are great fun for everyone with lots of Welsh flags flying. Many people pin a daffodil or leek - Wales national emblems - to their clothes and some, especially children, wear Welsh national costume, national team rugby shirts, or dress up as leeks, daffodils or even dragons
    </string>
    <string name="pancakeD">Diwrnod Crempog (Pancake Day)</string>
    <string name="pancakeDesc">
    Held on the eve of the Christian fasting period of Lent, Diwrnod Crempog (Pancake Day) sees people making and tucking into pancakes of all shapes and sizes.
    </string>
    <string name="lDay">National Laverbread Day</string>
    <string name="lDayDesc">
   A new addition to the Welsh calendar, we use 14 April to celebrate the oddly delicious Welsh staple of laverbread. Laverbread is the cooked version of ‘laver’, or porphyra seaweed, which is a diaphanous red algae found abundantly along Wales’ rocky coastline. The day was launched by The Pembrokeshire Beach Food Company in 2022, in celebration of this unusual national dish.
</string>

    <string name="easterD">Easter</string>
    <string name="easterDesc">The Christian holiday of Easter falls over one weekend in March or April, with the Monday and Friday both bank holidays (meaning many people don’t have to work). Religious processions are held (usually on the Sunday), while children hunt for chocolate eggs left by the Easter Bunny – a mythical giant rabbit with a penchant for chocolate (not to be confused with Welsh rarebit).</string>



    <string name="calanMai">Calan Mai</string>
    <string name="calanMaiDesc">
        Calan Mai, on 1 May, was traditionally considered the beginning of summer. Houses were decorated and bonfires lit, and big parties took place. Today, the first Monday in May is still a bank holiday (meaning many people don’t have to work).
</string>

    <string-array name="event_headings">
        <item>@string/stDwynd</item>
        <item>@string/DyddM</item>
        <item>@string/GwylName</item>
        <item>@string/stDavid</item>
        <item>@string/pancakeD</item>
        <item>@string/lDay</item>
        <item>@string/easterD</item>
        <item>@string/calanMai</item>
    </string-array>


    <string-array name="event_descriptions">
        <item>@string/stDwyndDesc</item>
        <item>@string/DyddMText</item>
        <item>@string/GwylDesc</item>
        <item>@string/stDavidDesc</item>
        <item>@string/pancakeDesc</item>
        <item>@string/lDayDesc</item>
        <item>@string/easterDesc</item>
        <item>@string/calanMaiDesc</item>


    </string-array>

    <string name="leave_review">Leave Review</string>
    <string name="not_Name">News and events in Wales here ! </string>
    <string name="not_Desc">Check this out to explore more about events in Wales</string>
    <string name="change_english">Change English</string>
    <string name="welsh">Welsh</string>
    <string name="menu_button">Menu button</string>
    <string name="image_slider">Image Slider</string>
    <string name="slider_images">Slider images</string>
    <string name="highlights_video">Highlights video</string>

</resources>